

## Afzal Ali

## Personal Profile

I am currently in my final year studying Computer Science at De Montfort University. With both my education and work experience I have gained a vast amount of knowledge and experience over the years. This includes extensive knowledge of software development as well as proficiency in several programming languages.

This has been very beneficial as it allowed me to put into practice things I have learnt into my working life. An example of this was the project management method PRINCE2. I was able to use the model to divide projects into manageable and controllable stages.

## **Education & Qualifications**

**De Montfort University** – Computer Science BSc (Hons)

Oct 2016 - May 2019

**First Year** – 2:1 (65%)

- 1. Programming in C [Unix, C, Trustworthy Software]
- 2. Computational Modelling [Set Theory, SQL, Haskell]
- 3. Elements of Computing [OS, Architecture, Networking]
- 4. Computer Law, Ethics & Portfolio [HTML Web Development, Social Engineering]

### **Second Year** – 2:1 (66%)

- 1. Object Oriented Software Design & Development [Java]
- 2. Organisations, Project Management, & Research [Java, Git]
- 3. Data Structures & Algorithms [Sequential Algorithms, Temporal Logic (C)]
- 4. Multi-tier Web Applications [Internet Protocols, Database (MySQL), Secure Scripting (PHP)]

## Third Year – 2:1 (Predicted)

- 1. Big Data
- 2. Interaction Design
- 3. IT Services Practice
- 4. Final Year Project [IOS App Development]
- 5. Front-End Web Development [HTML, CSS, JavaScript]
- 6. System Building Methods [IS Development Methodologies]
- 7. Popular Technology Ethics [Privacy, Artificial Intelligence, ICT4D]

#### **Beauchamp College - A Level**

Sep 2014 - July 2016

Applied ICT (A), Media Studies (B), Business Studies (C)

#### Beauchamp College - GCSE

Sep 2010 - July 2014

7 BTEC & GCSE A\* - C (Including Maths & English) Functional Skills Level 1 & 2 – Pass

## **Employment History**

# IT Support Technician - 1st Line Support | Manufacturing Cat Girl UK LTD

Feb 2017 - Aug 2018

- Providing first line technical support to all Employees.
- Managing the replacement of new and updated hardware.
- Responding to requests for technical assistance via phone or face-to-face.
- Being able to research solutions using available knowledge and resources.
- Carrying out daily checks on the computers to ensure backups are behaving as expected.
- Demonstrating good judgement when issues require escalation, intervention or further action.

## IT Support Assistant | Retail

Leicester Motor Spares

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016

- Carrying out audits on hardware and software installed.
- Integrating various IT applications to enable efficient work flow.
- Maintaining hardware/software and ensuring they are up to date.
- Using my troubleshooting skills to fix any issues with the systems.
- Using Microsoft Office applications in order to create detailed and complex reports.
- Initial installation and setup of an EPOS system to help monitor business performance and increase accuracy.

## **Customer Representative | Insurance Broker**

**Breeze Accident Solutions** 

Sep 2014 - Aug 2015

- · Collating information i.e. Claims data.
- Booking-out labour and materials to relevant jobs.
- Answering busy telephone lines, arranging appointments.
- Dealing with complaints, irate customers, and reporting incidents appropriately.
- General Admin Duties typing faxing photocopying, call handling, dealing with queries.
- Maintain consistency with service levels with professionalism and maintaining confidentiality.

## **Key Skills**

- · Attention to detail and strong organisational skills.
- Ability to design and create a website in pure HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Ability to take on multiple workloads, shift priorities and meet strict deadlines.
- Ability to manage small teams and to help colleagues reach their full potential.
- Knowledge with many creative software's such as XCode, Photoshop and Final Cut Pro.
- Can communicate effectively and confidently with staff, both technical and non-technical.
- A self-motivated individual, with the confidence to show initiative and work independently.
- Capable of using web creation IDE such as Microsoft Expressions and Adobe Dreamweaver.
- Strong problem-solving skills with a clear focus on displaying high customer service and satisfaction.

#### Additional Skills & Interest

**IT Skills:** Capable of using web creation IDE such as Microsoft Expressions and Adobe Dreamweaver. Intermediate user of MS including PowerPoint and Excel.

Driving Status: Full clean UK Driving Licence and access to own vehicle.

Languages: English, Gujarati (conversational), Hindi (conversational), Urdu (conversational).

**Tech Savvy:** From a young age I have always helped family & friends with computing issues that they have faced, such as backup or security issues. I find this very satisfying as I enjoy using my knowledge to help others.

**Car Enthusiast:** My enthusiasm for cars started back in 2014 when I passed my driving test. Ever since then I have been intrigued of the performance and aesthetic capabilities of vehicles. I regularly attend car meet-ups that are held around Leicester.

**Travelling:** I enjoy seeing and meeting new people from all parts of the world. It helps me put into perspective of how other people live their lives, compared to us in the UK.

## References

Available on request.